<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>No Third Party</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</description>
    <link>http://nothirdparty.com//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://nothirdparty.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 15:12:16 +0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 15:12:16 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kb: Test KB</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 19:54:46 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//kb/test/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//kb/test/</guid>
        
        
        <category>kb</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Why No Third Party?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Satoshi’s Nakamoto, the creator of Bitcoin, had clear intentions. Here is the first sentence of his email introducing his new creation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;I&#39;ve been working on a new electronic cash system that&#39;s fully
peer-to-peer, with no trusted third party.
&lt;cite&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto, &lt;a href=&quot;http://satoshi.nakamotoinstitute.org/emails/cryptography/1/#selection-19.0-14.6&quot;&gt;Bitcoin P2P e-cash paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Bitcoin, currency was government issued and electronic transactions required third party processing. Governments inflate money at will, stealing from entire populations. Many Argentinians have lost their life savings multiple times because of hyperinflation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Services like bank wires, PayPal, and Western Union require trusted entities to move money and verify transactions. Trusted entities must follow strict regulations and can freeze funds at any time. Cypriots, who put their trust in banks, were unable to withdrawal their own money during the 2013 bailouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin eliminates the need for trust in third parties. The supply of Bitcoin is known and visible to anyone who looks at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin&quot;&gt;the code&lt;/a&gt;. All bitcoin transactions are, like cash, made directly from person-to-person. Transactions are validated by Bitcoin miners. The network is for anyone to use and distributed–so no one entity has control and it cannot be shut down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the network whenever. Leave whenever. Nobody can prevent you from creating an account. No one can force you to use Bitcoin. No one can freeze your funds. Bitcoin is voluntary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the implications and benefits of finance with no third parties?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cryptographically Secure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;A purely peer-to-peer version of electronic cash would allow online payments to be sent directly from one party to another without going through a financial institution. Digital signatures provide part of the solution, but the main benefits are lost if a trusted third party is still required to prevent double-spending.
&lt;cite&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto, &lt;a href=&quot;http://nakamotoinstitute.org/bitcoin/#selection-37.4-37.325&quot;&gt;Bitcoin: A Peer-to-Peer Electronic Cash System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://coincenter.org/2014/12/bitcoin-mining/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin miners&lt;/a&gt; secure the network with proof of work. A bank account balance is simply a number in a database. You trust the bank to honor your balance. Bitcoin eliminates the need for trusted institutions. You can trust the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is like cash. If I own one bitcoin, I can be 100% sure I have one bitcoin. Bitcoin is secured by proof of work and can’t be counterfeited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust computers instead of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Peer-to-Peer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;I&#39;ve been working on a new electronic cash system that&#39;s fully
peer-to-peer, with no trusted third party.
&lt;cite&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto, &lt;a href=&quot;http://satoshi.nakamotoinstitute.org/emails/cryptography/1/#selection-19.0-14.6&quot;&gt;Bitcoin P2P e-cash paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer systems are voluntary. I can’t force you to use Bitcoin. You can’t force me. It’s a dumb network and accepts everyone. Bitcoin offers no barrier to entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin transactions are faster, global, and cheap. Bitcoin can be sent from Canada to Japan in minutes, for a cost of about $0.02 no matter how large the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Effortless Transactions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;With e-currency based on cryptographic proof, without the need to trust a third party middleman, money can be secure and transactions effortless.
&lt;cite&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto, &lt;a href=&quot;http://satoshi.nakamotoinstitute.org/posts/p2pfoundation/1/#selection-41.43-2.19&quot;&gt;Bitcoin open source implementation of P2P currency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial institutions slow down payments. Bitcoin makes sending money almost instant. There’s no bank, and no hours. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bitcoinuptime.com/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin works 24/7&lt;/a&gt;, anywhere with an internet connection. You can buy something or pay for services as fast as you can send an email. Payments, no matter how big or small, are now frictionless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;No Need for Trust (Third Party)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Commerce on the Internet has come to rely almost exclusively on financial institutions serving as trusted third parties to process electronic payments. While the system works well enough for most transactions, it still suffers from the inherent weaknesses of the trust based model.
&lt;cite&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto, &lt;a href=&quot;http://nakamotoinstitute.org/bitcoin/#selection-45.4-45.286&quot;&gt;Bitcoin: A Peer-to-Peer Electronic Cash System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin gives us financial freedom. Governments can’t control the currency supply and inflate it recklessly. There will only be 21 million bitcoin. This is Bitcoin’s killer app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Bitcoin you own your money, and no one else can freeze your funds or payments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;What is needed is an electronic payment system based on cryptographic proof instead of trust, allowing any two willing parties to transact directly with each other without the need for a trusted third party.
&lt;cite&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto, &lt;a href=&quot;http://nakamotoinstitute.org/bitcoin/#selection-49.4-49.211&quot;&gt;Bitcoin: A Peer-to-Peer Electronic Cash System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Future&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bitstein.org/blog/bitcoin-the-currency/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;em&gt; the currency&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will change the financial landscape. The internet made information and communication global, easy, and fast. Bitcoin will do the same for money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wallets/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin wallets&lt;/a&gt; give you access to the new world of money and finance. No Third Party provides you with the tools necessary to navigate the new peer-to-peer economy.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 19:54:46 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//blog/why-no-third-party/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//blog/why-no-third-party/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>meta</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: Mycelium</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Mycelium, founded in 2008, is a Bitcoin company with 35 employees located in Europe, Asia, and America. Mycelium offers mobile wallets for iPhone and Android. All of Mycelium’s applications are open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mycelium is a good option for new users, with basic features like watch-only addresses, cold storage spending, and HD accounts. Advanced options include TREZOR support, xpub/xpriv key exports, and decrypting BIP38 keys. Mycelium can also be used to restore a TREZOR seed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mycelium, founded in 2008, is a Bitcoin company with 35 employees located in Europe, Asia, and America. Mycelium offers mobile wallets for iPhone and Android. All of Mycelium’s applications are open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mycelium is a good option for new users, with basic features like watch-only addresses, cold storage spending, and HD accounts. Advanced options include TREZOR support, xpub/xpriv key exports, and decrypting BIP38 keys. Mycelium can also be used to restore a TREZOR seed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mobile wallet is only as secure as the device it’s running on. Mycelium encrypts all your data and keys. An unrooted (Android)/non-jailbroken (iOS) device should be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users can create a backup by writing down the 12 word seed provided in the app. If the phone is reset or lost, all funds can be recovered by re-entering the seed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mycelium is a hot wallet and should not be used to store a significant amount of funds.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 19:54:46 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/mycelium/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/mycelium/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>mobile</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
