<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>No Third Party</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</description>
    <link>http://nothirdparty.com//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://nothirdparty.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 20:05:05 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 20:05:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: Mycelium</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Mycelium, founded in 2008, is a Bitcoin company with 35 employees located in Europe, Asia, and America. Mycelium offers mobile wallets for iPhone and Android. All of Mycelium’s applications are open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mycelium is a good option for new users, with basic features like watch-only addresses, cold storage spending, and HD accounts. Advanced options include TREZOR support, xpub/xpriv key exports, and decrypting BIP38 keys. Mycelium can also be used to &lt;a href=&quot;/kb/restore-trezor-seed-mycelium-android/&quot;&gt;restore a TREZOR seed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mobile wallet is only as secure as the device it’s running on. Mycelium encrypts all your data and keys. An unrooted (Android)/non-jailbroken (iOS) device should be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users can create a backup by writing down the 12 word seed provided in the app. If the phone is reset or lost, all funds can be recovered by re-entering the seed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mycelium is a hot wallet and should not be used to store a significant amount of funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the iOS and Android apps connect directly to the Mycelium’s servers. Directly connecting to Mycelium’s servers allows for instant connection to the Bitcoin network, but reduces privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mycelium’s servers can view your IP address and wallet balance. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mycelium.com/wallet/FAQ.html#q019&quot;&gt;company website claims&lt;/a&gt; to not log IP information, but there is no way to be sure. Orbot/Tor can be used to hide your IP address from Mycelium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an HD wallet, a new address is created for every transaction and addresses are not re-used. Using a new address for each transaction helps prevent spying on your payments and funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mycelium developers recognized that users value their privacy, and plan to implement CoinJoin in future updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mycelium received a score of 50 out of 100 from the Open Bitcoin Privacy Project’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbitcoinprivacyproject.org/2015/05/spring-2015-wallet-privacy-rating-report/&quot;&gt;Spring 2015 report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 13:54:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/mycelium/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/mycelium/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>mobile</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: TREZOR</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;TREZOR launched in &lt;a href=&quot;http://satoshilabs.com/news/2014-08-07-trezor-sales-launched-buytrezor-com/&quot;&gt;August 2014&lt;/a&gt; as the first Bitcoin hardware wallet, offering secure cold storage plus the ability to spend with the convenience of a hot wallet. TREZOR is a small, key-sized device which connects to your computer with a USB cable. It stores your Bitcoin private keys offline and signs transactions. It can be safely used on a malware infected computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TREZOR is compatible with a number of wallets, including &lt;a href=&quot;/wallets/electrum/&quot;&gt;Electrum&lt;/a&gt;, MultiBit HD, and &lt;a href=&quot;/wallets/greenaddress/&quot;&gt;GreenAddress&lt;/a&gt; on desktop, &lt;a href=&quot;/wallets/greenbits/&quot;&gt;GreenBits&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/wallets/mycelium/&quot;&gt;Mycelium&lt;/a&gt; on Android, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://mytrezor.com&quot;&gt;myTREZOR.com&lt;/a&gt; on the web. Use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.satoshilabs.com/trezor-apps/extension.html&quot;&gt;TREZOR Chrome extension&lt;/a&gt; to manage your device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TREZOR can also be used as a secure login device on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.satoshilabs.com/trezor-apps/index.html&quot;&gt;number of websites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TREZOR provides top-notch security for bitcoin, protecting against both physical and virtual theft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TREZOR is an HD wallet where you control the private keys, so an entire wallet can be backed up with the 24 words generated on setup. The original 24-word seed is generated using RNG from the device and the computer. The seed is generated offline and displayed on the TREZOR’s screen, which ensures that the seed is never on an internet-connected device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A PIN code is required on setup, and required for spending. After each incorrect guess the wait between guesses is raised by a power of two. Making 30 guesses would take &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.satoshilabs.com/trezor-faq/threats.html&quot;&gt;17 years&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add a passphrase to the 24-word seed for extra security, which acts as a 25th word. You must remember the passphrase because the seed without the passphrase is not enough to recover the wallet. A passphrase offers more security, but if forgotten the wallet cannot be recovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can recover the entire wallet with the 24-word seed and passphrase if used, in the event that your TREZOR is lost or damaged. Recovery can be done with another TREZOR or with other wallets, like &lt;a href=&quot;/kb/restore-trezor-seed-electrum/&quot;&gt;Electrum&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;/kb/restore-trezor-seed-mycelium-android/&quot;&gt;Mycelium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TREZOR’s screen allows you to confirm that you’re sending to the intended recipient, but this does not prevent against phishing attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full overview of how TREZOR handles security threats can &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.satoshilabs.com/trezor-faq/threats.html&quot;&gt;be found on the Satoshi Labs website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TREZOR itself offers very good privacy. Satoshi Labs has no way of tracking your actions after you receive the device because it has no serial number. All of the software is open source. No usernames or passwords are needed when using TREZOR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privacy is determined by the wallet used with TREZOR: Electrum, MultiBit HD, and GreenAddress on desktop, GreenBits and Mycelium on Android, and myTREZOR.com on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 12:56:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/trezor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/trezor/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>hardware</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: Hive Mac</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hive is a native, elegant Bitcoin wallet for Mac. It aims to be ‘human-friendly’ and supports over 30 languages. Wallets created with the mobile/web version cannot be imported to Hive Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Private keys are encrypted with a password and stored on your computer.  Hive is a hot wallet and should be used for small amounts of Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your wallet and its keys can be backed up through Google Drive, Time Machine, or Dropbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hive Mac &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hivewallet/hive-mac/wiki/FAQ#can-i-create-more-than-one-address-or-multiple-wallets&quot;&gt;creates one address&lt;/a&gt; which must be used to receive all funds. This is detrimental to privacy and allows others to see your entire transaction history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hive Mac uses bitcoinj and SPV to connect to the Bitcoin network. Peers can connect your IP address to the single address used in Hive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 12:56:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/hive-mac/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/hive-mac/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>desktop</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: GreenBits</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;GreenBits is the native Android version of &lt;a href=&quot;/wallets/greenaddress/&quot;&gt;GreenAddress&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a multi-signature wallet that supports hardware wallets like TREZOR and Ledger. Seeds created with GreenAddress can be imported into GreenBits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, GreenBits is a 2 of 2 multisignature wallet. In this case, you control one private key and GreenAddress the other. GreenAddress must sign every transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GreenAddress claims that it will never sign a double-spend transaction. Users can send &amp;amp; receive to other GreenAddress and GreenBits users and receive instant confirmations, but this only works if the other party trusts GreenAddress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some features, like disabling 2FA and spending limits, must be set using GreenAddress and not GreenBits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mobile wallet is only as secure as the device it’s running on. GreenBits encrypts all your data and keys. An unrooted Android device should be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A backup is made by writing down the 24 word seed provided in the app. If the phone is reset or lost, all funds can be recovered by re-entering the seed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GreenBits offers a unique setup with its options of 2-2 wallets and 2-3 wallets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a 2 of 2 wallet, you control one key and GreenBits controls the other. If GreenBit’s servers go down funds cannot be spent immediately because it would be impossible to access GB’s signature. GreenBits solves this by providing nLocktime transactions, which release funds after a chosen period of time. You must set this up using GreenAddress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GreenBits relies on GreenAddress’s servers for transaction data, and also uses Electrum servers for extra verification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A user-set PIN is required to open your wallet each time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GreenAddress plans to add CoinJoin to GreenBits in a future update. GreenBits/GreenAddress know your IP address, balance, and addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an HD wallet, GreenBits generates a new address for every transaction and does not re-use addresses. Using a new address for each transaction helps prevent spying on your payments and funds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 12:56:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/greenbits/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/greenbits/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>mobile</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: GreenAddress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;GreenAddress is a multisignature Bitcoin wallet available on the web, desktop, Android, and iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default GA is a 2 of 2 wallet, which means you control one private key, and GA the other. GreenAddress must sign every transaction. This forces you to rely on GA, but offers true 2-factor authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GA claims it will never sign a double-spend transaction. You can send &amp;amp; receive to other GA users and receive instant confirmations, but this only works if both parties trust GreenAddress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can log into your GA account in watch-only mode. The account balance can be viewed and payments requested, but funds cannot be spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users may add spending limits to their accounts. Because GreenAdress controls one key, it can prevent all transactions which request more than the set limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GreenAddress’s servers provide transaction data, but also use Electrum servers for extra verification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GreenAddress offers a unique setup with its options of 2-2 wallets and 2-3 wallets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a 2 of 2 wallet, you control one key and GreenAddress the other. If GreenAddress’s servers go down, you cannot immediately spend funds because it would be impossible to access GA’s signature. GreenAddress solves this by providing nLocktime transactions, which release funds after a chosen period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GreenAddress has a PIN feature that is required to access funds. After three incorrect guesses, the wallet is erased from GA servers and recovery must be done with the seed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users in need of privacy should avoid linking their social networks to their account. GreenAddress plans to add CoinJoin in a future update. GA knows your IP address and balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an HD wallet, GreenAddress generates a new address for every transaction and does not re-use addresses. Using a new address for each transaction helps prevent spying on your payments and funds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 12:56:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/greenaddress/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/greenaddress/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
        <category>desktop</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: Electrum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Electrum is a light weight Bitcoin wallet for Mac, Linux, and Windows. It was created in November 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main features of Electrum are support for hardware wallets TREZOR and HW1, secure cold storage using an offline computer, and decentralized verification using SPV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electrum functions as a hot wallet or cold storage. For both wallet types, a 12 word seed is generated which allows you to backup and restore the entire wallet and its keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For cold storage, a seed is generated on a secure offline computer and written to a piece of paper. A master public key is created from the seed and imported into a separate Electrum install on your everyday computer. You can now view the wallet balance, accept payments, and create new addresses on a hot computer without the risk of funds being stolen. All transactions must be signed by the offline computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All Electrum private keys are encrypted and never leave your computer. Electrum wallets not using an offline computer should be treated as a hot wallet, as it’s still possible to have malware steal funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Electrum relies on third-party servers, the worst attack possible is the faking of transaction data. The servers have no way of accessing funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electrum is a lightweight Bitcoin client, and uses servers created by users to get transaction and balance information. A server has no way of knowing your actual identity, but does know your IP address, wallet addresses, and balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tor can be used to prevent the server from knowing your IP address, but cannot prevent the server from knowing that a list of addresses belong to one entity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some servers claim to not log or store information, but it is impossible to know for sure without setting up your own Electrum server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an HD wallet, Electrum generates a new address for every transaction and does not re-use addresses. Using a new address for each transaction helps prevent spying on your payments and funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electrum received a score of 46 out of 100 from the Open Bitcoin Privacy Project’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbitcoinprivacyproject.org/2015/05/spring-2015-wallet-privacy-rating-report/&quot;&gt;Spring 2015 report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 12:56:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/electrum/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/electrum/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>desktop</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: Coinkite</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Coinkite is a bitcoin platform with multisig wallets, merchant tools, and a developer API. It’s been in business for over 2 years and is based in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coinkite offers two kinds of wallets: a “Simple Wallet” where CK signs the transactions and holds the private keys, and “Multisig Vaults” where you control the keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Simple Wallet” is a BIP32 HD wallet where Coinkite’s HSM (Hardware Security Modules) securely generates and holds private keys. An encrypted back up of the keys is also sent to you by email. In this option you trade trust on Coinkite for convenience. The “Simple Wallet” should not be used to store large amounts of bitcoin. With full control over all “Simple Wallet” accounts and private keys, Coinkite can offer server side automation (i.e. Bitcoin Forwarding) but if shut down your account could be blocked. Coinkite has a dead-man-switch for service continuation in that case, releasing a global password to open the backups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coinkite’s “Multsig” wallets allow up 15 co-signers, which can be: signed by CK, an encrypted wallet stored on CK, a new key generated by CK, another CK user, the Ledger hardware wallet, or any offline generated BIP32 key. Coinkite’s multisig wallets give you 100% control of private keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users must trust Coinkite to provide the correct transaction data but also includes links with third party verification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coinkite doesn’t require email or any personal information on signup and can be accessed with a TOR onion address: http://gcvqzacplu4veul4.onion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can generate new addresses on deman, but the “quick deposit” feature reuses the same address. Address reuse makes it easy for others to observe your history on the blockchain and connect your addresses and funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CK has no US servers. All backups are in Switzerland and encrypted row by row.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 12:56:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/coinkite/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/coinkite/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: Coinbase</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Coinbase was founded in 2013. It’s a US-based Bitcoin company that has received over $100 million in VC funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accounts may be accessed through Coinbase’s website, or with its iPhone and Android applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users may create three types of wallets with Coinbase: wallet, vault, and multisig vault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wallet:&lt;/strong&gt; Coinbase controls the private keys. You must trust that Coinbase will keep the keys secure. You must also keep your account password safe, and also the 2FA code if activated. Coinbase is a VC backed company with over $100 million in funding and likely has a very strong security setup. However, the point of Bitcoin is that users have the ability to control their own money. Coinbase can shut down your account and block access to your funds at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vault:&lt;/strong&gt; Coinbase offers a unique solution for securing larger amounts of bitcoin. Bitcoin stored in a Vault account can be protected by multiple approvers. If a user adds two approvers to his vault, both must confirm that the withdrawal is valid before it processes. All withdrawals from Vaults take 48-hours to process. The time delay provides a safety net; if you see a withdrawal was requested that you did not make, the withdrawal may be cancelled. Like the hot wallet, you must trust Coinbase to secure vault funds. Vault accounts can also be shutdown by Coinbase at anytime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multisig Vault:&lt;/strong&gt; Coinbase understands that many users want complete control over their funds. Its multi-sig vault is a 2 of 3 wallet, where Coinbase has one key, one key is shared, and the third key is held by the account holder. Any two of the three keys allows spending of funds. If Coinbase goes down, you still have both the shared key and your own key. Funds cannot be held because the shared key is encrypted with your password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your name, phone number, email, and a number of other personal details are required. Coinbase knows your addresses and balance at all times and can connect this with your identity and IP address. You must trust Coinbase’s nodes to verify transaction data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Coinbase has buy/sell features, it must follow all KYC laws. There have been reports that it &lt;a href=&quot;http://cointelegraph.com/news/113207/coinbase-is-tracking-how-users-spend-their-bitcoins&quot;&gt;tracks how its users spend bitcoin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each payment request uses a new address, which helps prevent other users from connecting Bitcoin addresses together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coinbase received a score of 11 out of 100 from the Open Bitcoin Privacy Project’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://openbitcoinprivacyproject.org/2015/05/spring-2015-wallet-privacy-rating-report/&quot;&gt;Spring 2015 report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 12:56:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/coinbase/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/coinbase/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: Circle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Circle is a digital money company focused on making money “instant, secure, and free”. Its homepage only briefly mentions Bitcoin, and its wallet doesn’t do much more than receiving and spending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accounts may be accessed on Circle’s website and iPhone or Android app. Both apps allow the buying and selling of bitcoin and basic sending and receiving of payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Circle allows its customers to hold funds denominated in bitcoin or USD. Funds held as dollars are still be spent and received through the Bitcoin network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a web/hot wallet, Circle should not be used to store large amounts of bitcoin. With full control over all accounts and private keys, your funds may be frozen at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although all bitcoin held is insured, a loss is only covered if something goes wrong on Circle’s end. Your bitcoin is gone if your account is hacked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two-factor authentication is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your name, phone number, email, and a number of other personal details are required. You must trust Circle’s servers to verify transaction data. Circle knows your addresses and balances at all times and can connect this with your identity. Because of buy/sell features, it must also follow all KYC laws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each payment request uses a new address, which helps prevent other users from connecting Bitcoin addresses together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 12:56:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/circle/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/circle/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: Blockchain.info</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Blockchain.info is the world’s most popular blockchain explorer, and also offers a simple Bitcoin web wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain.info wallets can be accessed from in any web browser, apps for iPhone and Android, and browser extensions for Firefox and Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockchain.info encrypts your wallet in the browser and then stores it as a JSON on its server.  Blockchain.info has no access to funds and only your password can decrypt the file with your private keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A wallet backup can be stored anywhere, but its security is only as strong as the password used for encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain.info is not an HD wallet, so each new address is generated with RNG. Over &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coinsetter.com/bitcoin-news/2014/12/14/300-bitcoins-swept-blockchain-info-wallets-1992&quot;&gt;300 BTC were lost&lt;/a&gt; and luckily returned to BI users due to a weak RNG generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users have had &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bitcoinaffiliatenetwork.com/blog/bryan/how-hackers-used-tor-to-rob-blockchain-info-and-localbitcoins-users/&quot;&gt;funds stolen&lt;/a&gt; when using their wallet with Tor. Users who want to access through Tor should only do so through Blockchain.info’s hidden service: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockchainbdgpzk.onion/&quot;&gt;https://blockchainbdgpzk.onion/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain.info wallets should be accessed through the browser extensions or mobile apps for improved security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A password is the only information required to create a Blockchain.info wallet. A unique identifier is then created which allows you to login from other locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain.info allows you to use an email address or phone number for two-factor authentication. If notifications are active, BI must track your wallet’s public keys in order to issue alerts. Blockchain.info can connect email addresses or phone numbers to addresses if alerts are enabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain.info claims to only store a hash of the IP address a wallet was created with. Accessing its website through the Tor hidden service prevents leaking your IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must manually generate a new address for each transaction, which helps prevent spying or tracking of your payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain.info received two scores from the Open Bitcoin Privacy Project’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://openbitcoinprivacyproject.org/2015/05/spring-2015-wallet-privacy-rating-report/&quot;&gt;Spring 2015 report&lt;/a&gt;. Its web wallet received a score of 22 out of 100, and its Android app 14 out of 100.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 12:56:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/blockchain-info/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/blockchain-info/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
        <category>mobile</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
