<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>No Third Party</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</description>
    <link>http://nothirdparty.com//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://nothirdparty.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 11:58:02 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 11:58:02 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: GreenAddress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;GreenAddress is a multisignature Bitcoin wallet available on the web, desktop, Android, and iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default GA is a 2 of 2 wallet, which means you control one private key, and GA the other. GreenAddress must sign every transaction. This forces you to rely on GA, but offers true 2-factor authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GA claims it will never sign a double-spend transaction. You can send &amp;amp; receive to other GA users and receive instant confirmations, but this only works if both parties trust GreenAddress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can log into your GA account in watch-only mode. The account balance can be viewed and payments requested, but funds cannot be spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users may add spending limits to their accounts. Because GreenAdress controls one key, it can prevent all transactions which request more than the set limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GreenAddress’s servers provide transaction data, but also use Electrum servers for extra verification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GreenAddress offers a unique setup with its options of 2-2 wallets and 2-3 wallets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a 2 of 2 wallet, you control one key and GreenAddress the other. If GreenAddress’s servers go down, you cannot immediately spend funds because it would be impossible to access GA’s signature. GreenAddress solves this by providing nLocktime transactions, which release funds after a chosen period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GreenAddress has a PIN feature that is required to access funds. After three incorrect guesses, the wallet is erased from GA servers and recovery must be done with the seed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users in need of privacy should avoid linking their social networks to their account. GreenAddress plans to add CoinJoin in a future update. GA knows your IP address and balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an HD wallet, GreenAddress generates a new address for every transaction and does not re-use addresses. Using a new address for each transaction helps prevent spying on your payments and funds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 12:58:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/greenaddress/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/greenaddress/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
        <category>desktop</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: TREZOR</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;TREZOR launched in &lt;a href=&quot;http://satoshilabs.com/news/2014-08-07-trezor-sales-launched-buytrezor-com/&quot;&gt;August 2014&lt;/a&gt; as the first Bitcoin hardware wallet, offering secure cold storage plus the ability to spend with the convenience of a hot wallet. TREZOR is a small, key-sized device which connects to your computer with a USB cable. It stores your Bitcoin private keys offline and signs transactions. It can be safely used on a malware infected computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TREZOR is compatible with a number of wallets, including &lt;a href=&quot;/wallets/electrum/&quot;&gt;Electrum&lt;/a&gt;, MultiBit HD, and &lt;a href=&quot;/wallets/greenaddress/&quot;&gt;GreenAddress&lt;/a&gt; on desktop, &lt;a href=&quot;/wallets/greenbits/&quot;&gt;GreenBits&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/wallets/mycelium/&quot;&gt;Mycelium&lt;/a&gt; on Android, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://mytrezor.com&quot;&gt;myTREZOR.com&lt;/a&gt; on the web. Use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.satoshilabs.com/trezor-apps/extension.html&quot;&gt;TREZOR Chrome extension&lt;/a&gt; to manage your device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TREZOR can also be used as a secure login device on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.satoshilabs.com/trezor-apps/index.html&quot;&gt;number of websites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TREZOR provides top-notch security for bitcoin, protecting against both physical and virtual theft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TREZOR is an HD wallet where you control the private keys, so an entire wallet can be backed up with the 24 words generated on setup. The original 24-word seed is generated using RNG from the device and the computer. The seed is generated offline and displayed on the TREZOR’s screen, which ensures that the seed is never on an internet-connected device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A PIN code is required on setup, and required for spending. After each incorrect guess the wait between guesses is raised by a power of two. Making 30 guesses would take &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.satoshilabs.com/trezor-faq/threats.html&quot;&gt;17 years&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add a passphrase to the 24-word seed for extra security, which acts as a 25th word. You must remember the passphrase because the seed without the passphrase is not enough to recover the wallet. A passphrase offers more security, but if forgotten the wallet cannot be recovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can recover the entire wallet with the 24-word seed and passphrase if used, in the event that your TREZOR is lost or damaged. Recovery can be done with another TREZOR or with other wallets, like &lt;a href=&quot;/kb/restore-trezor-seed-electrum/&quot;&gt;Electrum&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;/kb/restore-trezor-seed-mycelium-android/&quot;&gt;Mycelium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TREZOR’s screen allows you to confirm that you’re sending to the intended recipient, but this does not prevent against phishing attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full overview of how TREZOR handles security threats can &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.satoshilabs.com/trezor-faq/threats.html&quot;&gt;be found on the Satoshi Labs website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TREZOR itself offers very good privacy. Satoshi Labs has no way of tracking your actions after you receive the device because it has no serial number. All of the software is open source. No usernames or passwords are needed when using TREZOR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privacy is determined by the wallet used with TREZOR: Electrum, MultiBit HD, and GreenAddress on desktop, GreenBits and Mycelium on Android, and myTREZOR.com on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 12:56:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/trezor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/trezor/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>hardware</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: Hive</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hive is an elegant, HD Bitcoin wallet available on the web, iPhone, and Android. It aims to be ‘human-friendly’, allows you control private keys, and offers basic send and receive features. Hive also supports Litecoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 12-word seed is generated upon wallet creation. The seed can be imported to Hive’s web wallet if the original wallet was made on Android/iOS, and vice-versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hive offers a feature called ‘Waggle’, which, using your geo-location, scans for other Hive users within 1 kilometer of your location. Payments can then be sent by clicking on a name of users near your location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mobile wallet is only as secure as the device it’s running on. Hive encrypts all data and keys. An unrooted (Android)/non-jailbroken (iOS) device should be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 12-word seed is generated on account creation. This seed is an account backup; all addresses and funds can be restored with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pin must be made on wallet creation, and is required upon opening the app or logging in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an HD wallet, Hive generates a new address for every transaction and does not re-use addresses. Using a new address for each transaction helps prevent spying on your payments and funds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 12:56:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/hive/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/hive/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>mobile</category>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: Bitcoin Wallet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin Wallet, or “Schildbach Wallet”, was the first mobile Bitcoin wallet and has over 700,000 users in the Google Play Store and about 100,000 users in the BlackBerry AppWorld.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mobile wallet is only as secure as the device it’s running on. An unrooted Android device should be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A file containing the wallet’s private keys are encrypted and stored on your phone. The file should be backed up to another location in case your phone is lost or reset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin Wallet is more secure than most mobile Bitcoin wallets, because it connects directly to the Bitcoin network with SPV. Most other wallets connect to centralized servers for transaction information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin Wallet is an HD wallet. It generates a new address for each transaction making it more difficult for spying or tracking your payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the wallet connects directly to the Bitcoin network peers can see your phone’s IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin wallet received a score of 46 out of 100 from the Open Bitcoin Privacy Project’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://openbitcoinprivacyproject.org/2015/05/spring-2015-wallet-privacy-rating-report/&quot;&gt;Spring 2015 report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 12:55:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/bitcoin-wallet/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/bitcoin-wallet/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>mobile</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: GreenBits</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;GreenBits is the native Android version of &lt;a href=&quot;/wallets/greenaddress/&quot;&gt;GreenAddress&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a multi-signature wallet that supports hardware wallets like TREZOR and Ledger. Seeds created with GreenAddress can be imported into GreenBits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, GreenBits is a 2 of 2 multisignature wallet. In this case, you control one private key and GreenAddress the other. GreenAddress must sign every transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GreenAddress claims that it will never sign a double-spend transaction. Users can send &amp;amp; receive to other GreenAddress and GreenBits users and receive instant confirmations, but this only works if the other party trusts GreenAddress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some features, like disabling 2FA and spending limits, must be set using GreenAddress and not GreenBits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mobile wallet is only as secure as the device it’s running on. GreenBits encrypts all your data and keys. An unrooted Android device should be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A backup is made by writing down the 24 word seed provided in the app. If the phone is reset or lost, all funds can be recovered by re-entering the seed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GreenBits offers a unique setup with its options of 2-2 wallets and 2-3 wallets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a 2 of 2 wallet, you control one key and GreenBits controls the other. If GreenBit’s servers go down funds cannot be spent immediately because it would be impossible to access GB’s signature. GreenBits solves this by providing nLocktime transactions, which release funds after a chosen period of time. You must set this up using GreenAddress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GreenBits relies on GreenAddress’s servers for transaction data, and also uses Electrum servers for extra verification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A user-set PIN is required to open your wallet each time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GreenAddress plans to add CoinJoin to GreenBits in a future update. GreenBits/GreenAddress know your IP address, balance, and addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an HD wallet, GreenBits generates a new address for every transaction and does not re-use addresses. Using a new address for each transaction helps prevent spying on your payments and funds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 12:54:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/greenbits/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/greenbits/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>mobile</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kb: Test KB</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 12:54:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//kb/test/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//kb/test/</guid>
        
        
        <category>kb</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blog: Why No Third Party?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Satoshi’s Nakamoto, the creator of Bitcoin, had clear intentions. Here is the first sentence of his email introducing his new creation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;I&#39;ve been working on a new electronic cash system that&#39;s fully
peer-to-peer, with no trusted third party.
&lt;cite&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto, &lt;a href=&quot;http://satoshi.nakamotoinstitute.org/emails/cryptography/1/#selection-19.0-14.6&quot;&gt;Bitcoin P2P e-cash paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Bitcoin, currency was government issued and electronic transactions required third party processing. Governments inflate money at will, stealing from entire populations. Many Argentinians have lost their life savings multiple times because of hyperinflation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Services like bank wires, PayPal, and Western Union require trusted entities to move money and verify transactions. Trusted entities must follow strict regulations and can freeze funds at any time. Cypriots, who put their trust in banks, were unable to withdrawal their own money during the 2013 bailouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin eliminates the need for trust in third parties. The supply of Bitcoin is known and visible to anyone who looks at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin&quot;&gt;the code&lt;/a&gt;. All bitcoin transactions are, like cash, made directly from person-to-person. Transactions are validated by Bitcoin miners. The network is for anyone to use and distributed–so no one entity has control and it cannot be shut down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the network whenever. Leave whenever. Nobody can prevent you from creating an account. No one can force you to use Bitcoin. No one can freeze your funds. Bitcoin is voluntary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the implications and benefits of finance with no third parties?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cryptographically Secure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;A purely peer-to-peer version of electronic cash would allow online payments to be sent directly from one party to another without going through a financial institution. Digital signatures provide part of the solution, but the main benefits are lost if a trusted third party is still required to prevent double-spending.
&lt;cite&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto, &lt;a href=&quot;http://nakamotoinstitute.org/bitcoin/#selection-37.4-37.325&quot;&gt;Bitcoin: A Peer-to-Peer Electronic Cash System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://coincenter.org/2014/12/bitcoin-mining/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin miners&lt;/a&gt; secure the network with proof of work. A bank account balance is simply a number in a database. You trust the bank to honor your balance. Bitcoin eliminates the need for trusted institutions. You can trust the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is like cash. If I own one bitcoin, I can be 100% sure I have one bitcoin. Bitcoin is secured by proof of work and can’t be counterfeited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust computers instead of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Peer-to-Peer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;I&#39;ve been working on a new electronic cash system that&#39;s fully
peer-to-peer, with no trusted third party.
&lt;cite&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto, &lt;a href=&quot;http://satoshi.nakamotoinstitute.org/emails/cryptography/1/#selection-19.0-14.6&quot;&gt;Bitcoin P2P e-cash paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer systems are voluntary. I can’t force you to use Bitcoin. You can’t force me. It’s a dumb network and accepts everyone. Bitcoin offers no barrier to entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin transactions are faster, global, and cheap. Bitcoin can be sent from Canada to Japan in minutes, for a cost of about $0.02 no matter how large the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Effortless Transactions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;With e-currency based on cryptographic proof, without the need to trust a third party middleman, money can be secure and transactions effortless.
&lt;cite&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto, &lt;a href=&quot;http://satoshi.nakamotoinstitute.org/posts/p2pfoundation/1/#selection-41.43-2.19&quot;&gt;Bitcoin open source implementation of P2P currency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial institutions slow down payments. Bitcoin makes sending money almost instant. There’s no bank, and no hours. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bitcoinuptime.com/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin works 24/7&lt;/a&gt;, anywhere with an internet connection. You can buy something or pay for services as fast as you can send an email. Payments, no matter how big or small, are now frictionless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;No Need for Trust (Third Party)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Commerce on the Internet has come to rely almost exclusively on financial institutions serving as trusted third parties to process electronic payments. While the system works well enough for most transactions, it still suffers from the inherent weaknesses of the trust based model.
&lt;cite&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto, &lt;a href=&quot;http://nakamotoinstitute.org/bitcoin/#selection-45.4-45.286&quot;&gt;Bitcoin: A Peer-to-Peer Electronic Cash System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin gives us financial freedom. Governments can’t control the currency supply and inflate it recklessly. There will only be 21 million bitcoin. This is Bitcoin’s killer app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Bitcoin you own your money, and no one else can freeze your funds or payments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;What is needed is an electronic payment system based on cryptographic proof instead of trust, allowing any two willing parties to transact directly with each other without the need for a trusted third party.
&lt;cite&gt;Satoshi Nakamoto, &lt;a href=&quot;http://nakamotoinstitute.org/bitcoin/#selection-49.4-49.211&quot;&gt;Bitcoin: A Peer-to-Peer Electronic Cash System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Future&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bitstein.org/blog/bitcoin-the-currency/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;em&gt; the currency&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; will change the financial landscape. The internet made information and communication global, easy, and fast. Bitcoin will do the same for money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wallets/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin wallets&lt;/a&gt; give you access to the new world of money and finance. No Third Party provides you with the tools necessary to navigate the new peer-to-peer economy.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 12:54:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//blog/why-no-third-party/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//blog/why-no-third-party/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>meta</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: Mycelium</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Mycelium, founded in 2008, is a Bitcoin company with 35 employees located in Europe, Asia, and America. Mycelium offers mobile wallets for iPhone and Android. All of Mycelium’s applications are open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mycelium is a good option for new users, with basic features like watch-only addresses, cold storage spending, and HD accounts. Advanced options include TREZOR support, xpub/xpriv key exports, and decrypting BIP38 keys. Mycelium can also be used to &lt;a href=&quot;/kb/restore-trezor-seed-mycelium-android/&quot;&gt;restore a TREZOR seed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mobile wallet is only as secure as the device it’s running on. Mycelium encrypts all your data and keys. An unrooted (Android)/non-jailbroken (iOS) device should be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users can create a backup by writing down the 12 word seed provided in the app. If the phone is reset or lost, all funds can be recovered by re-entering the seed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mycelium is a hot wallet and should not be used to store a significant amount of funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the iOS and Android apps connect directly to the Mycelium’s servers. Directly connecting to Mycelium’s servers allows for instant connection to the Bitcoin network, but reduces privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mycelium’s servers can view your IP address and wallet balance. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mycelium.com/wallet/FAQ.html#q019&quot;&gt;company website claims&lt;/a&gt; to not log IP information, but there is no way to be sure. Orbot/Tor can be used to hide your IP address from Mycelium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an HD wallet, a new address is created for every transaction and addresses are not re-used. Using a new address for each transaction helps prevent spying on your payments and funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mycelium developers recognized that users value their privacy, and plan to implement CoinJoin in future updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mycelium received a score of 50 out of 100 from the Open Bitcoin Privacy Project’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbitcoinprivacyproject.org/2015/05/spring-2015-wallet-privacy-rating-report/&quot;&gt;Spring 2015 report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 12:54:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/mycelium/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/mycelium/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>mobile</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: Hive Mac</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hive is a native, elegant Bitcoin wallet for Mac. It aims to be ‘human-friendly’ and supports over 30 languages. Wallets created with the mobile/web version cannot be imported to Hive Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Private keys are encrypted with a password and stored on your computer.  Hive is a hot wallet and should be used for small amounts of Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your wallet and its keys can be backed up through Google Drive, Time Machine, or Dropbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hive Mac &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hivewallet/hive-mac/wiki/FAQ#can-i-create-more-than-one-address-or-multiple-wallets&quot;&gt;creates one address&lt;/a&gt; which must be used to receive all funds. This is detrimental to privacy and allows others to see your entire transaction history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hive Mac uses bitcoinj and SPV to connect to the Bitcoin network. Peers can connect your IP address to the single address used in Hive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 12:54:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/hive-mac/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/hive-mac/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>desktop</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallets: Electrum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Electrum is a light weight Bitcoin wallet for Mac, Linux, and Windows. It was created in November 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main features of Electrum are support for hardware wallets TREZOR and HW1, secure cold storage using an offline computer, and decentralized verification using SPV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;security wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electrum functions as a hot wallet or cold storage. For both wallet types, a 12 word seed is generated which allows you to backup and restore the entire wallet and its keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For cold storage, a seed is generated on a secure offline computer and written to a piece of paper. A master public key is created from the seed and imported into a separate Electrum install on your everyday computer. You can now view the wallet balance, accept payments, and create new addresses on a hot computer without the risk of funds being stolen. All transactions must be signed by the offline computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All Electrum private keys are encrypted and never leave your computer. Electrum wallets not using an offline computer should be treated as a hot wallet, as it’s still possible to have malware steal funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Electrum relies on third-party servers, the worst attack possible is the faking of transaction data. The servers have no way of accessing funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;privacy wallet-sections&quot; id=&quot;privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electrum is a lightweight Bitcoin client, and uses servers created by users to get transaction and balance information. A server has no way of knowing your actual identity, but does know your IP address, wallet addresses, and balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tor can be used to prevent the server from knowing your IP address, but cannot prevent the server from knowing that a list of addresses belong to one entity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some servers claim to not log or store information, but it is impossible to know for sure without setting up your own Electrum server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an HD wallet, Electrum generates a new address for every transaction and does not re-use addresses. Using a new address for each transaction helps prevent spying on your payments and funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electrum received a score of 46 out of 100 from the Open Bitcoin Privacy Project’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbitcoinprivacyproject.org/2015/05/spring-2015-wallet-privacy-rating-report/&quot;&gt;Spring 2015 report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 12:54:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/electrum/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nothirdparty.com//wallets/electrum/</guid>
        
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        <category>desktop</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
